<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Popura Network</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Popura Network</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 05:47:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HyperModem</title>
      <link>/posts/hypermodem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 05:47:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hypermodem/</guid>
      <description>HyperModem is a low-powered electronic device that connects computers to the global off-the-grid communication network.
This device effectively creates a mesh network node which utilizes every available communication medium, be it a local wireless connection, the Internet or anything else.
Features  Easy to install mesh node for the Yggdrasil Network Enables access to the Yggdrasil Network for all LAN computers when connected to a regular SOHO router If a wireless adapter is available, creates an open WiFi access point for wireless peering, isolated from the Internet If the Internet connection works, automatically connects to the global overlay mesh Highly customizable open source software based on Openwrt  HyperModem built with a Raspberry Pi, connected to a regular SOHO router:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting all computers to the meshnet, but for lazy people</title>
      <link>/posts/yggdrasil-lazy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 14:58:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/yggdrasil-lazy/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites: a Raspberry Pi with a Raspberry Pi OS installed (aka Raspbian). Other armhf devices with Debian-based OSes might also work. Raspberry Pi must be connected to LAN, obviously.
Commands to run on a Pi:
wget https://github.com/popura-network/Popura/releases/download/v0.3.14%2Bpopura1/yggdrasil-lazy-0.3.14+popura1-armhf.deb -P /tmp/ sudo dpkg -i /tmp/yggdrasil-lazy-0.3.14+popura1-armhf.deb sudo systemctl start yggdrasil Final result: All computers in LAN have full access to the Yggdrasil Network. Raspberry Pi acts as a router and automatically keeps connection with the global Yggdrasil Network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Popura, an alternative Yggdrasil Network client</title>
      <link>/posts/about-popura/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 11:03:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/about-popura/</guid>
      <description>Popura is an alternative Yggdrasil Network client.
Yggdrasil Network is a peer-to-peer IPv6 network with link-local peer discovery, automatic end-to-end encryption, distributed IP address allocation, and DHT-based routing information exchange.
Popura uses the same Yggdrasil&amp;rsquo;s core API internally, but adds some useful and experimental features which the original client lacks.
Popura&amp;rsquo;s features:
 Automatic Internet peering Advertising /64 prefix to LAN Meshname naming system  By default, it works just like the original yggdrasil client, all features must be enabled manually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Popura Network website is online</title>
      <link>/posts/site-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 14:21:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/site-online/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a very low-traffic blog about the network infrastructure decentralization. Follow the RSS feed for updates or subscribe to the Telegram channel @PopuraChan.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>